

Soohwan Kim

ALRESEARCH ENGINEER · SOFTWARE ENGINEER

16F, Gangnam-daero 382 Merits Tower, Gangnam-gu, Seoul, 06232, Korea

□ (+82) 10-4564-4668 | 🗷 kaki.ai@tunib.ai | 🏕 sooftware.github.io | 🖸 sooftware | 🛅 Soo-hwan

"I dream of talking to artificial intelligence."

About Me

Current Co-founder and AI Research Engineer of TUNiB Inc. Former AI Research Engineer at Kakao Brain. I majored in Electronic & Communication Engineering and minored in Data Science at Kwangwoon university. My research interests include technologies for human-machine interaction, such as automatic speech recognition, speech synthesis, and open-domain dialogue. I enjoy software development and sometimes like to write my knowledge or thoughts. I want to be helpful to others through open source. You can check my github page (http://github.com/sooftware) to see what I am currently up to.

Education

Kwangwoon University

Seoul, South Korea

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING IN SCHOOL OF ELECTRONIC AND COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING

Mar. 2014 - Feb. 2021

- Major GPA: 3.90 / 4.5 / Total GPA: 3.67 / 4.5
- Major/Minor Courses: Capstone Design I-II, AI & Speech Signal Processing, Software Design, Machine Learning, Computer Architecture, Operating System, Data Structure & Algorithm, Data Mining, Network Programming, IoT System Design, Big Data Language, Big Data Processing & Application, Database, Digital Signal Processing, Statistical application, Object-Oriented Programming, Object-Oriented Programming Practice, Open-Source Software, System Programming, C programming, Mobile Programming, Data Communication, Computer Network, Basic Electronic Circuit Experiment I-II, Electronic Circuit Theory I-II, Digital Logic, Physics Electronic Technology, Engineering Math I-II, Probability and Irregular Signaling Theory, Probability and Statistics

Professional Experience

TUNIB Inc.Gangnam, Seoul

Co-founder, Al Research Engineer

Mar. 2021 - Present

- Create conversational digital humans who people emotionally engage with.
- Research and develop the latest NLP technology.
- Webpage: www.tunib.ai [link]

Kakao Brain Pangyo, Gyunggi

AI RESEARCH ENGINEER

Nov. 2020 - Mar. 2021

- Research & develop speech and natural language processing fields
- Development PORORO: Platform Of neuRal mOdels for natuRal language prOcessing [link]

Internships _____

Kakao Brain Pangyo, Gyunggi

AI RESEARCH INTERN

Aug. 2020 - Nov. 2020

- Research & Development of automatic speech recognition models
- Development of multilingual speech synthesis model with support for twelve Languages

Spoken Language Lab (of Sogang Univ.)

Mapo, Seoul

Undergraduate Researcher

Apr. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- · Studies speech recognition techniques based on various machine learning algorithms (e.g. deep learning). [link]
- Research End-to-End Automatic Speech Recognition Models

Military Service _____

ROKMC Served and discharged from Republic of Korea Marine Corps as Signaller, Sergeant, 2015.09 - 2017.06

Publication

- 2021 KoSpeech: Open-Source Toolkit for End-to-End Korean Speech Recognition, ELSEVIER, SIMPAC
- 2020 **End-to-End Speech Recognition Models in English, Korean and Chinese**, Bachelor's Graduation Thesis

Project Experience

PORORO: Platform Of neuRal mOdels for natuRal language prOcessing

Kakao Brain

Maintainer, Team Member

Sep. 2020 - Mar. 2021

- PORORO performs Natural Language Processing and Speech-related tasks. [link]
- It is easy to solve various subtasks in the natural language and speech processing field by simply passing the task name.

Multilingual Text-To-Speech

Kakao Brain Oct. 2020 - Feb. 2021

• Development of a model that supports multilingual Text-To-Speech.

Supports 11 multi-language, Cross-lingual Voice Style Transfer, and Code-Switching functions. [link]

English, Chinese, and Korean End-to-End Automatic Speech Recognition

Kakao Brain

THE PERSON IN CHARGE

THE PERSON IN CHARGE

Aug. 2020 - Oct. 2020

- Listen, Attend and Spell, Transformer, and Wav2vec 2.0 Model experiments
- · Speech recognition speecd and performance comparison by output-units (character, grapheme, etc.)

KoSpeech: Open-Source Toolkit for End-to-End Korean Speech Recognition

Kwangwoon Univ. Jan. 2020 - Feb. 2021

TEAM LEADER

- Modular and extensible end-to-end Korean automatic speech recognition (ASR) toolkit
- It is the most popular Korean speech recognition task in gitHub. [link]

Extracurricular Activity

Speech Paper Reading

Study

GROUP MEMBER

Dec. 2020 - Present

- · Weekly meeting where people who work in the field of Speech gather and read papers.
- Reading a paper and summarizing its contents [link]

NLP Paper Reading

Study

Aug. 2018 - Present

 GROUP MEMBER
 Sep. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- · Kakao Brain Natural Language Processing Team's weekly paper reading study
- Reading a paper and summarizing its contents [link]

Technical Blog Blog

• Technical posting of deep learning, programming, signal processing, paper review etc.

· Having more than 100 subscribers and an average of 200 visitors a day [link] [link]

Skills

WRITER

Programming Python, Java, C/C++, Shell Script, SQL, Android, Arduino, Assembly, HTML

Deep Learning PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, Fairseq, Transformers, PyTorchLightning, Wav2letter, Faiss, Hydra

Data Analysis Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-learn, BeautifulSoup, Selenium, NLTK

Awards & Honors

AWARDS

2020.11	President's Award	(1st Place)	, Kwangwoon	Engineering Festival
---------	-------------------	-------------	-------------	----------------------

2020.11 **People's Choice Award**, Kwangwoon Engineering Festival

2019.10 Finalist (12th Place), Naver A.I Hackathon - Speech

2019.09 Finalist, Kwangwoon University software start-up idea contest - Fall

2019.04 People's Choice Award, Kwangwoon University software start-up idea contest - Spring

2018.08 Best Award, Samsung Multi-Campus in Java-based Algorithm for SW Development

HONORS

2020.03 **School Representative**, 5G-based ICT Convergence Service Idea Contest

2020.03 Excellent Scholarship, Samsong Scholarship

2019.03 Excellent Scholarship, Samsong Scholarship

2019.03 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University

2018.09 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University

2018.03 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University